James Schreiber

Address: 16 William St South Yarra, VIC 3141 Mob: +61 408 767 485

Email: James.Schreiber93@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/jschrbr

Portfolio: https://jschrbr.github.io/portfolio/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/techsmechs/

Summary

I'm driven by automation, both digital and physical, I have a BSc. in Mechanical Engineering, with working experience in the Aerospace Industry.

Recently, I graduated as a Full-Stack Developer from Monash University and earned a Professional Certificate in IT Automation with Python.

I'm a utility player, and a quick learner, I can comprehend and solve problems across a variety of disciplines, notably mechanical & electronic assemblies, as well as a handful of coding languages and frameworks (C/C++, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js, mySQL, mongoDB, Rect.js and Angular).

I have successfully onboarded dozens into demanding technical roles.

I have Introduced a new product and digital work instructions into an existing aerospace production environment, within a year.

I have built web-based applications to display job data and manage product resources.

I have a variety of experience with IoT applications, and have enabled the control of my garage door through google's voice assistant. My technical aptitude makes me a strong addition to any engineering team.

Skills

Highly computer literate across Linux, Mac and Windows.

Mechanical Design and Analysis:

Solidworks, PTC Creo, Inventor Fusion and Rhinoceros 5 w/ Grasshopper.

Ansys Workbench, Spaceclaim and MSC Mentat.

Specialisations:

Process Design and Optimisation.

Mechatronic Testing and Development.

Troubleshooting and Repair of Advanced Mechatronic Systems.

Fabrication and Manufacturing, both Design and Assembly.

Embedded/Web:

HTML, Javascript, CSS, Node, Shell, Python, React.js, Angular, Matlab, C/C++, VBA, Assembler.

Electrical Design and Assembly:

Eagle, Circuitmaker, PCB assembly and IPC Certified cable assembly.

Projects

Trakka TLX Searchlight New Product Introduction | whitepaper

Brought a new aerospace product from R&D to Production.

Leading the implementation of a flagship product from prototype to standard production within aerospace standards, within one year.

- Tested, developed and documented the assembly process
- Trained employee on technically advanced topics and procedures.
- Designed and implemented processes to maintain traceability of required testing and measurements through Production.

Roboteam Customer Support for the NZDF | website

Providing technical support for a project with the NZDF EOD squadron.

- Learned to disassemble, maintain and reassemble several products and variants of advanced mechatronic systems within two months.
- Trained operators on basic maintenance and safe operation.

Twitter clone | Firebase, React.js, Redux and Material-UI | demo

Twitter clone built from a tutorial but refactored for async/await. (Code available on request).

- Utilizes firebase authentication, functions, database and hosting.
- User, Post and Error data is dispatched through Redux.
- Material-UI used for styling. Server validated errors are handled with styling..

Second-opinion | ML5.js, P5.js and MaterializeCSS | git | demo

A simple machine learning web application where the user can train a custom model based on visual likes and dislikes.

- Utilizes ML5.js to create custom like/dislike classifiers extracted from the MobileNet model.
- DOM manipulation through P5.js
- Styled using MaterializeCSS

employ-EE | Node and MySQL | git

A node base CLI application for keeping track of employees and role/department specific information.

- Utilizes ML5.js to create custom like/dislike classifiers extracted from the MobileNet model.
- DOM manipulation through P5.js
- Styled using MaterializeCSS

Simple-bin | MaterializeCSS, HTML, Javascript | git | demo

Just a really simple dec. to bin calculator. Material styling using MaterializeCSS..

- Nice looking calculator, styled to intuit the user on how binary to decimal conversions work.
- Styled using MaterializeCSS

Self-taught Cross-Disciplinary Skills

- Electronic hardware design and assembly
- A large variety of coding languages with generally small learning curve to adopt new languages/libraries/frameworks
- Hand assembly, from manual machining to welding.
- A variety of home automation projects utilising low cost IoT hardware and custom toolchains.
- Restoration and desktop milling machine with custom controllers.

Work Experience

Trakka Tech - Technical Support Consultant

April 2020-Present, Melbourne.

- Successfully implemented a new product into an regulated production environment.
- Implemented electronic work instruction to streamlining the new product implementation.
- Onboarded dozens of staff in highly technical roles.

Trakka Systems - Process Improvement Manager and Production Engineer

Feb 2019 -Feb 2020, Melbourne

- Successfully implemented a new product into an regulated production environment.
- Implemented electronic work instruction to streamlining the new product implementation.
- Onboarded dozens of staff in highly demanding technical roles.

Trakka Systems - Process Engineer

Feb 2017 - Feb 2019, Melbourne

- Managed Production environment handling non-conformances and other issues that could affect on time delivery.
- Implemented changes in existing documentation within the guidelines of the industry requirements.
- Plentiful experience in hands-on assembly in Production and R&D environments.

Kevin Stahlmon - Apprentice

Aug 2014 - Dec 2016, Byron Bay

- Learned the basics of working with hand and power tools.
- Initial exposure to larger scale cross disciplinary projects.

Starseed Gardens - Technical Officer

Feb 2013 - Dec 2016, Byron Bay

• An opportunity to learn and expose myself to a variety of fields including agriculture, mechanical, electrical, plumbing and IT.

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

Monash University, Victoria (2020)

Bachelors of Mechanical Engineering

Griffith University, Gold Coast (2013-2017)

VCE

Bialik College, Victoria (2010-2011)

Certifications/Licenses

Google's Professional Certificate in IT Automation with Python Certified IPC Specialists under IPC-620 C (Cable and Wire Harness Standard)